I just needed to make the actual content
to everyone else inaccessible so how do
I going to do that well cookie bombing
okay yeah my man uses cookie bombing
that's what I'm talking
about best part of acting when you can
just you know critical things
[Music]
right yeah dude
hey what's up y'all before we dive into
the episode I wanted to tell you a
little bit about the sponsor which is
appropriately appomni I worked at
appomni for four and a half years before
leaving to do full-time bug bounty in
this podcast and our guest of this
episode Aaron Castello is currently
working there appomni is the best SAS
security for the Enterprise product um
on the market they do everything from
taking audit logs and using those events
in order to normalize them and enrich
them and then uh send alerts basically
Downstream to the companies to the to
the security operations team they also
have specific insights which are
basically like a security expert in your
pocket like a SAS expert in your pocket
there is policies which you can use to
monitor the systems um configurations
and settings across all of your SAS in a
single place um there's another feature
called ask Omni which is the AI feature
that I built over the course of the last
year which allows you to chat in natural
language with all of your SAS security
data points whether it is your policies
or your alerts or what have you and it
comes up with like really nice graphs
and heat maps and stuff like that as
well if you're interested um if you're a
stakeholder if you're you know a ceso at
a big at a big org and you're interested
in um upping your s security game you
can reach out to appomni atomy.com a p m
ni.com thanks back to the
show me and Aaron were at a um at an
event for app Omni and it was it was me
and him and then our manager at the time
for labs his name is Alec and Alec is
like exmilitary obssessed with Fitness
like he literally like runs cold plunges
does BJJ like every day oh my gosh and
we were just looking around all the
vendors like yeah I think we could take
any of them yeah Aon Alec we could take
anybody any any booth in the in the
building it's pretty funny that's great
man yeah dude it I don't know there's
something about I feel like there's a
higher percentage of people in security
that are actually just totally ripped
too like is that is that my is that just
my impression because there's like that
stigma going around of like the 400
pound hacker and their mom's basement or
whatever but I'm like most of the
hackers I know are like actually pretty
ripped yeah I I will say it's probably
because at least in the bug bount space
everyone's really high agency right I
mean everybody's working really hard
they learn a ton they go dominate their
field so they're probably also
dominating their health in a lot of ways
yeah yeah yeah for sure man all right
cool so let's get let's let's get back
on track eron um thanks so much for
joining us on the Pod man
um the way we do it here on the critical
thinking podcast is we bring on a guest
we say their name Aaron Castello uh and
we say hey man show us a bug so what
what what what bug did you bring for us
today yeah so today I'll be talking
about a bug that I
found God prob late 2020 early
2021 most likely the ladder and it's
combining your SAS based Mis conf fig
because we'll be talking a lot about SAS
Security today and also more traditional
kind of web hacking uh some kind of juny
Breer behaviors um so right off the bat
um for priv program on on hacker one um
a travel
company that had a uh one of the
subdomains running on Salesforce so it
was built entirely on Salesforce and
integrated with Salesforce um platform
in that way so now getting to the site
it was mostly on authenticated access
and they had this functionality that
would allow for one of their customers
to upload uh documents and detail a
support request right so talking about
issues with passport or flight or
anything like that sure sure um and then
based of the kinds of uh things that
they were saying on that form I thought
okay some of these attachments could be
sensitive like oh make sure your ID is
cleared that kind of thing so I
uploaded uh basic blank image random
text I was trafficking uh all of it
through through
burp and what I noticed was the actual
image was being uploaded to an
external um booket provider which is
very very unusual because
Salesforce has its own storage for for
for images and and documents right okay
yeah and and how it was actually doing
this was using uh Apex and we'll get to
that later on that's from Salesforce
nomenclature but Apex is like server
side code on the platform so it's kind
of java syntax it's an object ored
orientated programming language and so
in the actual request itself when I sent
those
details uh it one of the parameters
being provided was a path and the
response was a URL of the image and also
along with that a a a key to access the
image on this booket so you navigate to
the URL you get
access by removing the key from the URL
and the external storage booket you no
longer have access okay okay so it's
like assigned access sort of thing
exactly exactly so I was kind of
planning around with it and tested out
some couple of things
so I managed to validate okay yeah I
could replace another user's like file
if I wanted to right but then again the
actual file names were were randomized
so unlikely um I was also able to
Traverse the path so in the request I
was able to modify the path that was
being uploaded to the
bucket um once again potentially writing
as of the directory of writing sensitive
files that kind of thing but we need to
know the names of these files right now
one key thing that I noticed was there
wasn't really any file uh file type
validation being performed um I couldn't
execute any like server side right
anything right um but I could upload
things like HTML SVG XML uh that kind of
stuff um just nothing server side so
using a technique that I actually read
from I think it was file
descriptor
um which is about appcash
manifests
okay I feel like a lot of the newer
bookies won't know what this is because
it appcash manifest pretty much replaced
by service
workers
but the the what I was able to do was I
could upload an appcash manifest and
additional HTML files and so how the the
the appcash manifests work is uh it's a
special file type and it's used for um
providing the ability that for for users
to access
content offline on a website so it
stores the content of a page in your
browser so the Manifest defines um what
what content is effec be cached in your
browser so there's an interesting
attribute within this appc manifest
called a
fallback
so any file in that same directory um or
sorry every user's file was uploaded in
the same directory and so the appcash
Manifest would apply to every file in
the directory and so the followback what
it specifies is a path to a file in that
directory that is requested
if the other files become inaccessible
so
right
so using the technique from file
descriptor what I was able to do was I
uploaded one file that was specified as
the fallback this is a HTML file that
would
exfiltrate um the the URL so when the
fallback redirects this file it would
exfiltrate where it was being redirected
from to my own web server ah and that
was the path of the in the key exactly
right I would grab that key I just
needed to make the actual content to
everyone else inaccessible so how do I
going to do that well cookie bombing
okay yeah my man uses cookie bombing
that's what I'm talking about
underated very very underrated so I was
able to upload a HTML file that's
specified at the beginning use this
manifest and then proceed to just fill
the browser with like junk cookies and
so when that happens when the cookies
become too large the content becomes
inaccessible in the browser so the
actual attack Vector here or
theoretically what it would
be is you would upload these files set
the stage and when a support engineer
goes to view that file it would load the
Manifest it would basically dos their
browser and they'd think okay so like
what's what's going on here I don't know
what's happening maybe the file is
corrupted or something so they go to
view another case and look at their
files when that file is viewed it would
kick in the fallback which points to
basically um my HTML that performs
Ajax to my my own um externally hosted
web server and it would capture that
other customers signing key and so I was
I'd be able to access potentially
sensitive documents through that um so
that's kind of combining the SAS uh
misconfiguration there with your typical
xlit and that's why I found it
interesting there is a little bit of
user input required there but uh I think
it's a nice little chain it kind of
shows what can do when you're bit of a
jock ball trades in a lot of areas yeah
no I I I love that dude and I love
anything that utilizes one I just
freaking love anything that utilizes
cookie bombing man cookie bombing is
just such a fun technique and I just am
so like in awe of the fact that that
still exists you know like why why do we
allow the browser to just set so many
cookies that it freaks out the web
server right and and and causes these uh
these mistakes to happen um so I I love
it when it's mixed with service worker
with appcache and uh the the ability to
exfiltrate those those paths and those
those keys um is just perfect and
combining that you know I was thinking
okay so you know we use this attack on
the victim and then when they go and
submit a service request then I'll get
access to their files but really the
you're right the more impactful thing is
hit the engineer you know that that goes
through and is actually triaging each
one of these tickets and then you get
access to all of the paths and all of
the tickets that they click on that's
right that's exactly it and and you know
part of that attack and why it wasn't
very applicable to other customers was
that once the the form was submitted it
was like fire and forget so you couldn't
actually view what you just submitted
you'd probably get an email in a couple
days from a support engineer saying oh I
just received your ticket right so yeah
it was it a very very interesting bug um
I think it was classified as as a High
um probably being a bit generous there
but I think the novelty gave me a few
few extra bonus points dude do you think
that actually this kind of question for
both of you all do you think that if it
was loading any kind of like summary
images or thumbnails or anything like
that that it could have potentially
triggered a bunch on a single page yeah
yeah that kind neat depending on how the
back end was written that's it exactly
yeah so they could have been like a
restricted area that Salesforce platform
that had like preview thumbnails of all
these of all these support requests and
it was just firing off all of them you
know so yeah that's sweet dude well uh
Aaron now I'll officially do your intro
now that we've got a bug under our and
people know that you're well worth your
salt though I can also vouch for you I
worked at um at app Omni where Aaron
currently works with him for three or
maybe four years um it's been it's been
uh a long time since we both worked
there together obviously I recently left
so I uh left Aaron standing as the only
member left of the appomni labs team but
um I can personally vouch for how uh
bright Aaron is and I think that his
depth of knowledge and expertise in the
SAS security space specifically is
completely paralleled as most bug
hunters will know if you've seen his
blog so his blog is enumerated doie and
um specifically there are Salesforce and
uh service now misconfigurations that
have made him and others lots of money
from bug Bounty but more importantly has
secured the the data of probably
hundreds of millions of users I know at
app Omni it's like we check for these
things of course but then lots of bug
Hunters have reported them on companies
that don't use appomni or or other
providers and I'm sure that the other
competitors and the SAS security space
are checking for these same things so um
so yeah so it's a pleasure Aaron to
interview you and I know that Jess and I
are both really excited to to hear your
opinions uh specifically let's dive
straight into just misconfigurations in
general um you know you and I have
talked a lot about this but our
listeners maybe have not thought deeply
about it uh what makes misconfiguration
such a really um both lucrative and just
like neat thing for buck Hunters to look
for yeah absolutely so if you think of a
tradition
web op vulnerability in like a custom in
a custom site it's a onof right so you
find like a SQL injection they use
parameterized queries or something to to
fix it and that's it done now you're off
hunting for maybe other injection points
you're hunting for other kind of
classifications of
vulnerabilities but with this kind of
stuff it's it's SAS right so every
customer for example using Salesforce
did a to deploy a publicly accessible
site the core of it is the same across
all these different organizations so the
core apis are the same how the access
controls are configured are the same so
if you find a way to exploit
misconfigured access controls by let's
say you're unauthenticated and you can
pull data if they've accidentally made
some data public you you can just use
the exact same payload on another
customer so it's basically like an it's
like an end day in that regard right
it's not not exactly a zero day because
these are things the customer could go
in and fix uh presumably yeah and that's
and that's the kind of important
distinction here is like I classify
these as misconfigurations because the
customers themselves typically 99% of
the time have accidentally made some
data some sensitive data public the
vendor so Salesforce service now have
just provided them with the tools and
said like Hey we're a powerful platform
you can do a lot with us use this how
you want to and generally they will say
things like yeah just don't you know
don't touch this or like look out for
this and people will ignore it because
they want the easy button right and by
pressing the easy button it's like okay
you've just leaked five million people's
vaccination records you know that's
that's exactly what happens that exact
scenario has happen multiple times yeah
yeah yeah that's crazy dude and and I
think that's one of the beautiful things
about it all as well is like you know
the customer it's a third- party
software right which is so that we we
know that there are patterns to it we
know that there are tricks to it um that
because we can go and work with the
software ourselves get our hands on it
sort of mold around with it um and then
the problem that you normally have with
thirdparty software is that you know the
company's going to kick it back and be
like nah that's third party vone you
know not our problem we're not going to
pay you for that but with this one
because they induced the vulnerability
themselves you know in the system then I
don't know I my I would suspect that you
almost always get paid for these have
you have you run into situations where
they're like uh yeah but it's Salesforce
and you know given some excuses like
that or do they get paid like 80 90% of
the time I mean so typically when I was
reporting all this stuff it's before
anything's necessarily like public right
so there's a ton of push back of like
what is this what is like how did you
find this like what's going on here and
there's a bit of panic and then they'll
go to the vendor and the vendor will be
like yeah you you messed up your access
controls here like you did this right
and then they're like oh okay and
they'll pay you so since the Inception
of most of my research and the
application of it by a lot of B beny
Hunters um globally it's become a lot
more understood so I haven't heard of
push back in a long time um and so it's
it's it's a safe safe bug to to hunt for
right you're not going to get an NA at
all unless it's at a scope of course
right yeah I guess I guess Justin it
would kind of only be potentially you
know shut shut down or closed as
informative if it was not like an open
scope program for most bug Bounty
companies where it's open scope then you
know if if they own it or it's their
customers they're probably going to pay
for it yeah um the one thing that I was
going to mention uh about this was that
I think uh Aon specifically and I have
have farmed this uh just like one or two
times on some stuff the the biggest
issues that we ran into and I know that
Aaron has to fight with sometimes that
app Omni is that some of these
vulnerabilities are in a gray area if
they are defaultly configured that way
Justin so you know like SAS security is
near impossible to configure properly
for a lot of companies because they're
basically full-blown operating systems
and these companies spend an entire year
setting up their service now or their or
their workday or their or their
Salesforce um but when the configuration
is kind of by default exposing something
then it gets kind of tricky about
whether or not it's it's on the
provider's fault or if it's like on the
implementer fault yeah yeah I can
definitely see that it's happened a
couple times um and typically how how we
will handle those responsibly is if you
do find an endpoint that can be used to
exfiltrate data or leak data out of and
you
notice that there is a default access
control that coming with the system out
of the box you would well I would
recommend to submit the access control
issue to the
vendor and then for the rest of the bugs
that you find that are misconfigured by
the customer those would be would be on
their side of the shed responsibility
model yeah and and I imagine it would be
a little bit difficult too like you're
going to almost run into I don't want to
break anything sort of responses from
the SAS vendors where they're like oh
yeah that shouldn't be the default but I
don't have any data on whether if I just
globally flip this switch for everyone
whether it's going to break anything so
it's kind of hard for me to like
globally be like oh maybe I should just
turn this off yeah um so yeah I don't
know I I guess that's sort of the best
you know situation where it's it's
default but it's something that they can
change um is that like so let's talk a
little bit about your methodology
because you looking at your blog and
looking at your research you know you
you've hit a bunch of different uh
sasses and and identified you know
misconfigurations across a lot of
different sasses when you are are going
into this scenario is this like your
your Holy Grail is like this insecure
default or do you really like to try to
find something that is not default um
but is like the most common
configuration that the customer has to
do to get the product to work yeah
that's a great question and and also
going to set the the lay of the land
here when we kind use certain n clature
really um
so for these kinds of bugs you need two
things in order to kind of retreat this
information you need an API endpoint if
you want to call it that uh to pull the
data from and then you need data that is
exposed okay so these apis these end
points these the existence of these is
not a
vulnerability these are used to serve a
purpose and often some core
functionality okay um
on the flip side the access
controls those being misconfigured is on
the customer on the out of the box
misconfiguration is in the vendor so I
actually want to avoid situations in
which the vendor has misconfigured
something because once I report a
misconfigured Access Control they they
just fix it right and what I'm hoping
for
is when applying these techniques to a
ton of Co customers in an authorized
fashion obviously um they've all
misconfigured access controls so it's
fully on them you know that's the the
the dream really and it is kind of my
bread and butter it's this kind of data
exposure um
because there's a lot of noise about
like third party risk and supply chain
risk and a lot of the high-profile SAS
attacks by kind of these thread actors
are through like supply chain so like a
compromised service account for an
integration and stuff like that we have
to remember like you need a foothold
there you needed to have access to that
in some way gained access this stuff I
find so much more interesting because
you're unauthenticated like you don't
need anything right so there's no prior
access no prior knowledge needed and
that way it's far more dangerous and I
can honestly say handle my heart from
doing this for four years now or five
years actually that
um I've probably compromised in an
authorized fashion through book by
platforms things like that like 100x
what these thread actors are
compromising to supply chain oh yeah
this this is honestly the real risk with
SAS it's like this unknown like what are
these API endpoints like what are they
used for that kind of thing um and and
to speak to my methodology a little bit
yeah please I never I never approach
these platforms I try not to it's hard
but I I never approach these platforms
with the intent of like hacking
generally
speaking I I sign up these platforms if
they have some kind of free developer
account or something like that and I
just try and become an expert on the
platform on its functionality the use
cases all of that um so when when I was
hunting or not say hunting when I was
becoming an
expert on service now that's actually
how I found my service no disclosure
right where there was massively wide
spread misconfigurations in customer
access controls and there's API
endpoints that you could pull data from
so these API endpoints were not
documented anywhere they were Legacy and
Legacy is where the gold is I know with
you know all the AI stuff um is very
very hip and trendy and it introduces a
lot of new attx service and I get it but
like let's not forget the stuff that's
I'm sitting there 10 15 years yeah and
and isn't even necessarily in the
Forefront of the documentation or
something like that is deprecated but
not even disabled exactly and I'm I'm
thinking probably you know you say you
come in here and you kind of just try to
become an expert on it and that's what
we say on the Pod all the time is you
know whenever you're hacking something
you just need to become the world expert
on that application no matter what it is
right exactly um and and I think that
can be accomplished a lot of times by
reading the docs but I think there's
also a little bit of a hacker mentality
that needs to go into it as well where
you're looking at the you know you've
read the docs or whatever but then
you're actually looking at the code
you're looking at the JavaScript files
you're looking at the front end you know
you're you're seeing the way that all of
these uh calls interact together and
sort of reverse engineering and being
like hey what's that weird sketchy
little API over there right um I think
that's where we we see a lot of those
bugs pop up too yeah and Aaron um maybe
didn't say that specifically but that's
uh often what he is having to do at app
Omni he'll be he'll be given a a like a
new SAS vendor and be and been and be
told to like hey figure this out so we
can implement it for the engineers and
he basically does like that initial
Recon of like okay yeah we'll use these
API points to pull the users and we'll
use these API points to pull the groups
and so he kind of has to become an
expert in it in order to like hand that
off to our developers or to hand off to
the developers at app Omni so they can
go through and get it all so he's kind
of like by necessity learning it as an
expert which is really cool that's
awesome it's it's honestly even even
further than not with with service now
like I built the integration like the
whole so I'm I'm actually a well I
didn't renew it um last year but I'm
like a certified platform administrator
and a certified developer have the
certifications for I went through so I
actually built the the whole uh
integration in the app um but so so what
happened there with the service now
findings was
like I I thought to myself
okay this is like a Salesforce
equivalent in respect that it's very
very powerful and very
customizable so I thought to myself
there must be some way that they let
organizations like put record data on a
page okay MH
so think about uh an implementation like
uh customer support requests surely
there's a lot of use cases where someone
wants to deploy a site on service
now um and allow for customers to
authenticate or sign up and authenticate
and submit requests and then view their
ticket information and that ticket
information is being pulled from the
database right so I thought there must
this function must exist somewhere and I
could not find it anywhere so I this and
this is just a testament to how hard
work outweighs intelligence because I'm
living proof
okay service now um actually let you see
every table in the schema okay so
there's hundreds and hundreds of tables
I went through every single table and
was like what is this what is this
what is this for like hundreds and
that's how it came across
widgets um so I was looking through the
widgets
and I I was using a bit of filtering
because I knew the the Syntax for the um
the on platform serers side programming
language so I was looking for for
widgets that were querying um for like
user input like tables yeah that's how
it came across simple list uh an un
ordered list which the both of the
widgets that they're public by default
um and for people watching like a widget
is effectively just an API endpoint and
it would take user input uh specifically
like a table name and and a column
name and it would let a user read data
from that table and that column if the
access controls are misconfigured mhm uh
so that's how it came across it so it
was just through sheer countless errors
and and nights going through the schema
uh hunting for this stuff yeah so when
you and I were hunting this and
Reporting it I noticed that there were
like for most implementations there was
a few that were like almost always
shared which like weren't that sensitive
like it was like maybe like I don't know
usernames but then for some customers we
found that like the entire internal
knowledge base was exposed do you like
is this do was there like what was the
functionality that made them or like you
know did you ever figure out why the um
certain fields or certain tables were by
default enabled was it for that customer
support portal or was it for something
else well all right
so I think to answer your question
because I remember I think I remember
the company you're you're talking about
um and that was a knowledge based
disclosure right and I so I have two
blogs I have one specifically for like
table data and then one specifically for
um knowledge based exposures and that's
just because the access controls are
implemented differently got it um but
the knowledge base um so they just
misconfigured their access controls
effectively what would happened at that
point was they just didn't put any
access controls on but because no one
knew that these endpoints existed these
widgets they were like oh it's not
public right um and I also remember for
for that affected organization this was
actually
insane their knowledge base had like
access tokens in it and like for like
for external systems was like it was a
disaster the kind of stuff that they're
storing in in knowledge based articles
is is wild right like it it it was crazy
um and that was actually an interesting
one
because when I released the article on
knowledge-based disclosures which used a
different
widget um service now actually stepped
in and basically saved other customers
and said yeah we're just going to lock
down all of your access controls um and
know they were communicating this very
very well with their customers to say
like hey just letting you know there's
going to happen things might break like
we'll give you some time to like you
know work work around it but that was
did they do this manually like do you
think that they they staff members had
to go in and be like all right you know
this is what the current situation is
this is how the access controls should
be they just deployed it they just
deployed production everyone's stuff but
they naturally it wasn't like granular
it was like blast here's access controls
go yeah so they they T all this stuff
beforehand naturally um and and because
they were trying to gauge the best way
of solving this problem other than
because they were sending Communications
out to customers and saying like hey
your Access Control suck like
everything's exposed but the issue with
that is not everyone reads their
emails so some stuff was still exposed
stuff was just exposed everywhere um so
they kind of took that brave leap and I
have to give them kudos for that because
they put their customers in a much
better position it's a difficult
position they've now got to uh some
organizations may need to figure out a
way around it to implement whatever
functionality they they they have there
but um they're they're better off for it
and look I'm sure some of them have just
undone it they just yeah just flip it
back because if they were using it for
like an external Dev documentation or
developer portal or something then where
there was nothing sensitive in it it was
totally fine to be that way they could
have just rolled that back the other
thing I was going to ask you about the
one of the I think it's the simple list
widget is the um I noticed that when you
and I reported it there was some
specific U there was like one specific
endpoint we were using but then I was
like like your blog got posted and I
remember seeing a bunch of people like
Tweeting or talking about it afterwards
where they were using a completely
different type of payload it was like we
were using like a post request or
something and they were using like a get
request at a different endpoint do you
remember the nuances around that or like
um you know does that ring any bells
there were there were like a there were
like five or six maybe a little more um
different widgets that you could use um
so I mean that's that's really where
where it comes from
um there was limitations with some uh
some way did s to kind of filter through
the data which could be helpful when
looking for particularly sensitive
things like phone numbers or whatever it
is um but all of those got hit with the
the patch so they did roll out a kind of
a defense in depth mechanism like a
security guard rail for those those
widgets uh in which they effectively
made it so organizations would need to
like set all these system properties in
order to allow for data to be exposed to
them um and I know because I I I feel
talking about this I know you guys were
curious like is there any more widgets
like can we get more widgets um not that
I know of unfortunately uh the
knowledge-based one I believe still
works so there's like a ton of knowledge
based ones they all still work um
there's
no I don't believe there's any like
prerequisite such as a system property
or anything that needs to be set by the
customer um so those are still
applicable sweet yeah I've got two more
quick things about service now before we
pivot to something else the first thing
is one thing that I saw that I'm sure
you've seen a few times Justin which is
really cool I know we have a lot of
program managers listening is um four
SAS uh specific things if you're worried
about them being misconfigured and you
want to give uh researchers a specific
Target to hunt for you can actually put
a flag like you can create a user where
their details are a flag and then if
someone's able to get access to that
they can submit it for a vulnerability
or in service now it can be a ticket or
it could be a a user user details like
user pii or something and like a sign or
put a flag there I know that T-Mobile
has done that and it's a pretty cool way
to like have someone validate that they
got access to something they shouldn't
have have inside one of these SAS
platforms um but what I was going to ask
you Aaron specifically was one if you
have any comments on that of course you
can mention it but do you think there
like what would be if there's any
hackers out there that have been looking
at service now because I'm pretty sure
they have a a private program floating
around or at least a public VDP what
what are some areas for future research
um on service now that uh maybe has been
interesting to you if there's a specific
API path or piece of functionality or
feature that recently came out um that
you would recommend if if the Hacker's
looking for something to dig into what
should they dig
into that's a great question that's a
fantastic question um what did you not
have time to get back to I guess is the
real question I know you've got notes
over there probably not well um I have
looked at at a ton of stuff um I would
say things like like ux data Brokers um
so that's another kind of like API
endpoint uh data
Brokers I'd recommend playing around
with the UI Builder and so
you're designing like a front end and
you've got a couple of different um
means to which you can implement the
backend functionality so looking through
those available API endpoints that can
also return data uh playing around with
those and see if there's kind of another
maybe not like a simple list but just's
any kind of um maybe lack of validation
on a Pam or see if you can get around it
yeah that's that's definitely what I
recommend but still kind of Legacy stuff
um I know they are doing a lot with with
AI as well so naturally I mean that's
kind of your your wheelhouse um but yeah
I think I when it comes to data exposure
I've I've rinsed service now fairly hard
um look elsewhere leave it alone yeah
that's funny
man on that note actually when you're
talking about what I recommend for for
hackers and SAS apps and things like
that um I would definitely recommend
that this will require some money some
some prior
input if you got a group of skills
people because a lot of these these SAS
apps cost a lot of money like a lot
we're talking I think I've seen like 20K
a month in like at a peak oh my God so
band together with a group of guys group
of book bny hunters get yourself like a
productional license for
some big SAS
organization
um not going to say which ones but ones
that are old um uh and ensure that you
know the the you're getting the right
license you know something that allows
you to implement that kind of external
functionality and I've have no doubt as
well like five or six people or up to
eight people just hacking on the one
platform like you're making money back
definitely but it is that is kind of the
the barrier uh or the entry barrier for
people getting into this it's like the
instances cost a lot of money and do
have to go through a bit of a process
sometimes to to buy
it's it's a little bit it's crazy too
because you say wow you know 20 grand up
to 20 grand a month and I'm like oh my
gosh that's crazy and then you think
about like wow we pop one critical you
know on like one of these major
organizations and that could be 20 grand
easy you know um I think that the
investment is definitely there yeah yeah
it's funny we've had that in in abam
where I I've made an argument I was like
look we need this license like I'm
telling you there's stuff here we need
this I'm tell like okay for one month
you've got one month so for one month I
just sweat it out I'm like come on
return on investment
please yeah so before before Justin
takes us to the uh to talking about
Salesforce or one of these other topics
we've got listed here I did want to
reframe one thing you said you know I
think you said you have basically rent
service now for all they're worth but
just like as a reframe to you personally
and to the audience I think it's like a
really healthy reminder to be like no
what you actually did is helped secure
hundreds or thousands of companies and
and and hundreds of millions of users
data and so uh I'm thankful to to your
work in that regard and I think thaten
listeners and customers should be too so
yeah absolutely yeah big shout out to
service now as well because they handled
it very very well given the
circumstances um so Kudos kudos to them
too okay so I'm dealing with two you
know appomni guys here so I I got to
just take a step back in and sort of um
recap for the for the SAS for the Newbie
SAS hacker like myself you know what
what exactly the approach is here so
first service now what you guys are
saying is we need to utilize these
specific sections uh relating to widgets
which I imagine is you know loading
widgets onto a page you know on the
front end or whatever the API is
associated with that um to leak data
about the given objects inside inside
service now is that that sort of like
the tldr of this approach tldr widgets
API end
points provide a table name provide
column names or whatever kind of input
to leak the data and if there's
misconfigured access controls then the
data will be shown yeah and if listeners
are confused like Aaron's two blogs on
service now are extremely clear it's
like it walks you through exactly what
they all me and exactly the request to
use so yeah yeah and so the the widget
piece there the re reason why using
widget here is important is because
that's that piece that you mentioned
before where it's like that's the API
endpoint that we use to pull to pull
that data out and there could be other
API endpoints as well that can give us
access to that that misconfigured data
so so the the overall problem here is
that there's bad access controls you
know on the data itself but then we are
using the widget related API endpoints
to extract and and to get at that data
that is actually has bad access controls
is that right completely correct yeah
okay and so then what you were saying
before was like okay now we got to find
another Avenue maybe it's not simple
widget like it was before or simple list
widget um but maybe you know it's in the
the ux uh what was that piece could you
say it one more time the ux designer
Brokers data Brokers yeah yeah yeah
there's a ton of Legacy widget like apis
out there so look for those hidden gems
and maybe you'll find something that you
could use to hack thousand data Brokers
okay and that's a part of the like ux
builder stuff that's related to service
now and then what we'd be looking for is
another one of those sort of um API end
points where we could query the data
that is already misconfigured because of
access control stuff right and and and I
think I think the interesting thing here
is that the fix you know you said
was and and correct me if I'm wrong here
not necessarily to fix it at the widget
level which is that API endpoint um but
but to fix the overall Access Control
problem that that happens with with
service now so service now pushed a
bunch of access control updates to their
users so so now even if we find another
API endpoint where we can query
misconfigured data I mean are do you
expect to see as
grossly misconfigured access controls as
we did see the first time or do you
think that those access controls have
been shed up in large part oh yeah
you'll still see so many so many 100%
there's going to be a ton of regressions
absolutely um
and I want to touch on that point of yes
service now pushed out some by default
Access Control changes and yes at the
widget in the widget code they
implemented some guard rails where it's
like
the organization has to flip a flag for
the widget to be
accessible
um but too many organizations are going
to fix it on that latter part they'll be
like well I can just undo these Access
Control changes now because the widget
isn't
accessible um that's what's gonna happen
right okay gotcha so there's two fixes
sh up the access controls and then fix
your widget and a lot of people will be
like ah okay widget's not accessible no
worries and then leave access controls
wide open and that's why we go search
for another API endpoint another path
through data Brokers or whatever where
we can get at this misconfigured data
yeah and I also think like they're going
to be adding uh new features as well
Justin a and a lot of SAS providers have
this is like a thing Aaron always looks
for because he kind of coached me and
helped me on this as well when doing
sass security research is like basically
guest user access and so that's kind of
like the you know key word that kind of
makes a lot of this possible is there's
just um and guest user is almost like
one step away from unof in fact you know
most people could still probably
consider it Uno but if you think about
it in the context of the application it
still is giving you some sort of token
it's giving you some sort of cookie or
it's giving you some sort of API token
that is expected to have like little to
no sensitive data access but often it
does get misconfigured to have it and I
would say one step further than that
Justin like let's say service now fixed
all unoth and all guest user stuff like
there's going to be some organizations
where like you can get like as a
customer you can get like a support
access and now support access might be
able to have access to like all all
cross customers right there like so each
of these API Points each of these
widgets each of these pieces of
functionality could be vulnerable at any
step they might be on off they might be
accessed with like a no privilege token
and then they might be they might be
misconfigured with a privilege token so
those are kind of the ways that I think
about it gotcha Erin any comments on
that and how like the different roles
are utilized by the different
organizations I'll touch on that more
when we talk about the Salesforce things
um on a few time for for Power Platform
too I'll be talking about that a lot
okay sweet yeah let's hop right into it
then Salesforce um and and I sort of
read over the whole Salesforce thing and
man it's it's it makes me want to go
hack on this stuff man it's it's crazy
the way that they've got this whole
thing configured um and I guess the
first question that I wanted to say here
was this article was written this
legendary article this is like like
whenever anybody talks about Salesforce
they're like oh they're using Salesforce
I'm like ah uh this blog go you know
like I always just like copy paste this
blog i' be like ha hack it with this um
and so very legendary blog on the space
um and and it was but it was written in
2020 so five years ago um and I'm
wondering if uh all of the stuff I kind
of know the answer to this already but
I'm wondering you know uh how much of
this is still applicable and uh you know
has much changed since the 2020 write up
of of this very applicable very very
applicable exact same payload I found
this I found this on a program like two
weeks ago so oh my God um there there
has been some minor minor changes um
with respect to some of the payloads
where they've actually baked in some
restrictions uh and people won't really
know this stuff unless they're very
sales for Savvy um
so what those restrictions were or one
example restriction was so using one of
those um payloads from the
article at that time you were able to
access both record data so data being
stored in tables and also data being
stored in what are called custom
settings uh now typically custom
settings are very
sensitive so what Salesforce did there
they made it so that that pay those
payloads couldn't be used to access
custom settings um so there there's like
minor kind of baked in restrictions like
that but um yeah I mean Joseph found
something two weeks ago so it's still
very very applicable and upom we' have
so many sales for Salesforce customers
and prospective customers we still see
this stuff right like it's it's wild
yeah absolutely and so um there there's
lots of different pieces to Salesforce
security there's like the um Apex
classes there's the Salesforce object
query language um and all that stuff
what would you say is like the 8020 the
the things that we are going to get the
most you know bang for our buck for with
like knowing about those Salesforce
misconfigurations and security control
all right I'll talk about three things
here well it's really two things and
then one is just like a tip so the first
is the access control misconfigurations
in the same manner uh that we spoke
about with respect to service now so
using the payloads um that are outlined
in in my blog looking for objects that
are publicly accessible uh that you can
read sensitive data from okay okay um so
there's payloads in there that let you
enumerate all the object names and then
you can just iterate the extraction
payload effectively over those object
names that's that's
one two is the Apex so the custom Apex
uh code uh so briefly what that is I
spoke about it in the initial um kind of
Bo Boog talk Apex is like server side
code it's forces kind of proprietary
language right and some object
orientated
language Apex
provides the business logic so if
someone clicks a button on a for it
could fire off some Apex that would
maybe retrieve some data or insert some
data um so it's that kind of server side
logic so is that written by the
customer so yes it is written by the
customer now there is some the Box a
button and and then it does like an RPC
call is this like a remote procedure
call type thing on on the server or
right so okay we're getting into it okay
so effectively
um these so in sales force you can have
what I know known as digital um
experiences previously they're called
lightning communities so it's just like
a website to put on Salesforce okay
and uh how it was built a while ago was
through What I Call Aura components and
these are just front end components
components like forms and
buttons and you would pair an AA
component like a form or login form or
something with an apex class that was or
what we call Aura enabled so when Apex
is Aura enabled it means it is
accessible via the aura
API okay and that's what we can get
access to it through so if you look at
the payloads in my in my article you'll
notice that those payloads are being
sent to the or API because that's the
API endpoint that exists Within These
public sites supp put on
Salesforce so yeah it's the aura kind of
UI framework being paired with the kind
of backend Apex um business logic and
where these kind of issues arise and why
this is kind of like the 8020 is you've
got a lot of customers implementing
their own functionality so when I spoke
about that bug for some reason they were
were integrating with an external
storage booket through Apex so really
what was probably probably happening
there
was using um the aura API that kind of
Apex was being
called and then in the in the core code
uh The Core Apex code in the Salesforce
platform on the server side that Apex
was probably pulling some credentials
from a credential store like name
credentials or something in Salesforce
and then
pushing that to the um the storage
booket so I have a specific paper on
apex I don't know how applicable it is
today with because I talk about how you
can like find what parameters are
required you can find Apex methods that
aren't even like in use yeah so
definitely give that a look to
understand the fundamentals but it's
like think of it as just like Ora
enabled Apex are just custom API
endpoints
that's that's all it is and and you say
there's there's a way to enumerate those
from the external attack surface without
like having to read like The JavaScript
files or whatever client side code we
have in place you you you would need to
to kind of pull apart the the client
side a little bit okay got so there is
some I think that I mean I'd hope just
by now there's some automated tool to do
this for you but uh you might have to do
it
manually um so you're effectively
pulling apart um yeah as you said like
the JavaScript and looking for the
methods um that exposed to the or API
and you know what what inputs are they
expecting okay this parameter and it's a
string and you play around with those
and so the reason I I mention that this
is so important is take a scenario in
which you're applying method one of
querying for exposed objects right and
let's say all the access controls are
locked down okay so you're out of look
nothing you can
do
well you can develop a aex in an
insecure way so you can develop Apex in
a way that it just doesn't respect
access
controls I've seen running as like a
system user or something on the back end
so yeah it's called
um like without sharing is when it's
running in system context when it's
running in that context it effectively
means that whatever it's
accessing it's it's not respecting whose
data you can read so you could I've seen
Apex that just pulls all users so
straight away okay you've got phone
numbers everything addresses or whatever
it is there's a lot of different things
that you can do there is what you
alluded to earlier the soc um queer
language which is like SQL um very very
similar it it just doesn't allow for any
DML so like no insert update delete just
just read only so you can have instances
where user input is being put into a
um so query but it's not being sanitized
so it opens up these kind of very SQL
injection like attacks um so I speak
about that I believe in the in the Apex
white paper as
well uh and and that's why it's so
important because what might be
restricted by access controls may not be
restricted by the this kind of custom
Apex that's being developed and exposed
as an API Aaron you should tell Justin
the way that I don't remember if it was
you or if soie actually figured it out
and then he told us and you used it or
something later but um I assume that it
was probably your finding how did you uh
what was the workaround you found for
leaking named I think it's fixed at this
point but there was a way to get around
leaking named
credentials yeah yeah Justin I love this
dude this sounds great yeah
so um yeah it's okay this is an
interesting one
so the name credentials in Salesforce I
very brief mentioned it um it's a method
in which Salesforce can integrate with
an external platform so you as a let's
say Salesforce administrator you log
into Salesforce and you go to the name
credential page and you can basically
specify uh again typically an API
endpoint and you can specify how it
authenticate so you can provide like an
access token you can provide like so
this is just straight up credentials
like these are like Secrets basically
you can provide credentials to it and um
once you save
that you can call it from Apex so it's
just a way that allows developers to
call an external system in an
authenticated manner without needing to
embed the credentials in the code in the
Apex code yeah exactly right so it's
just
safer
um now there's two ways you can set them
credentials up so one is is or it was in
the past called named principle named
principle means that anyone who's
accessing um performing this call out to
an external system through
Apex everyone's using the same type of
credentials it's the credentials that
were provided when it was created and
then there's also per user which means
that each individual user has their own
okay um now we all know that no one's
using the lad okay everyone's using the
shared credential that's why this
happened um and so
the issue with kind like hacking this
stuff
is you can't just run
Apex right unauthenticated like you
can't just run server side code like
that would be insane right um but if you
were to go to a site toloy in Salesforce
that allowed you to sign
up you then what's called generally a
community site user and you've got extra
privileges just by signing up self sign
up take two
seconds and there is another API import
that lets and it's called like execute
Anonymous and it let lets you run Apex
so so you just sign up like you go
through the normal like sign up to
create a support user or whatever so I
can like submit my ticket or whatever
and now that I've got this community
user I can just run Apex code within
within the the Privileges of my specific
user as an anonymous user wow okay
you're not you're not Anonymous you're
like authenticated you're just like a
low priv user you're nextal user um but
the issue was like okay yes this execute
Anonymous Apex it does run with SH like
it doesn't run in system context so it's
only in your privileges with named
credentials if it was set up as a named
principle aka the credentials are the
you the CRS used are shared by everyone
you could just
bruteforce the
the name
credential no and all you need to do
that is
basically
um you would so when you perform a call
out through Apex to name with name
credential it's just a label so you
could say like Amazon okay and the Apex
you'd say call out um colon Amazon so
you would just brute force all the
commonly used names so you could go to
GitHub scrape a ton of name names throw
them into a word list and through that
mechanism you could see the responses
from these apis and you're authenticated
because you're using the credentials
that were set up by the Admin and
they're all shared under your name
principle um and the best part as well
is you can modify the path so you can
actually like access
resources that outside of what was
intended so yeah it was a really
interesting one um that was once again
another one of those things where
because I had that on platform knowledge
I knew there was an execute Anonymous
API I knew that you needed to be
somewhat authenticated to use it dude
that's that's gonna be a new term some
somewhat authenticated like I I so many
bugs happen in the somewhat
authenticated uh you know environment
that's that's really key and and so
that's the third thing I was going to
talk about when it when J asked that
question so the first was kind of that
misconfigured access girls for objects
the second was um custom Apex custom
Apex exposed as an or API and the third
is just privilege escalation Yourself by
signing up okay you would have you have
no idea how many lightning communities
I've tested that were so locked down
what you un authenticated you sign up
two seconds later you click it
confirmation Link in your inbox you're
now authenticated as a community site
user and all of a sudden everything's
accessible everything's just totally
accessible you'll also then have access
to not only more objects chances are
you'll be able to see um some some
leaked data that you couldn't see before
we'll also have more custom Apex so
you're just expanding on it is it so or
Apex that sometimes will return like an
obus skated response for secrets and
then there you there you found there was
a way around it by like renaming it as a
part of the query or renaming the the
key as a part of
[Music]
the there's a lot of stuff I can't talk
about okay we G have to that who knows
um yeah there's there's a lot of of
interesting attack vectors so yeah I I
would advise everyone to uh just read
the original paper read the or the
original numerator blog read the Apex
white paper on abom um and look into
kind of soc as well see how that
underlying those underlying database
calls are working with Apex and yeah
it's very very fruitful may maybe want a
clarification here Aon because I know
that people have messaged me about this
in the past sockel injection is not
always sensitive correct so if just
because you found a so injection it
doesn't mean necessarily that there's
going to be sensitive data accessible to
the uh authentication context that
you're in right got to validate these
things 100% right it's you can't just
throw well this wouldn't work for SOC
anyway but you know with like SQL
injection people like throw in a dash or
like a percentage 27 um it's like oh it
threw an error so like tons of sensitive
stuff and you find out like the DB is
just empty it's like unused so same
thing here make sure you validate what
is accessible and what is not accessible
like it's it's crucial because the last
thing you want to do is go through all
the effort of writing a report to be hit
with an NA and like I think like a 10 is
it still like minus 10 reputation fine
yeah yeah so it's brutal so don't be
that so what is your go-to payload to
like let's say you had soel injection
what is your go-to at least like thing
to try to achieve with sofel
injection uh sensitive information
disclosure right because we're we we are
limited with respect to the operations
we can perform it's only read and you
are also limited to the context of the
query so what object is being accessed
what's being pulled and how is it being
pulled so the same way if you look at
SQL
injection your injection Point can be in
different Clauses so it could be like
the where claw
right same with SOC
injection depending on for example if
you have a Apex is performing a so query
and your user input is being part of
like uh it's being used in the like
operator okay you you you might be able
to get some good sensitive information
um through like using like wild cards
right to just pull everything or yeah is
wild card in soal the percent
symbol I believe so I believe so um
could be
okay okay solid so so there's three let
me I'm just going to repeat it back
there's three primary things there we're
hitting these objects which is kind of
like tables right if I understand
correctly so you know trying to see if
there are any tables that we have access
to that we shouldn't be able to have
access to right through through the uh
through the aura API um same thing we're
hitting Apex classes where it's like
okay let's see if we can enumerate all
the Apex classes either via you know
looking at the client side or like
that's exactly look through the client
side we just look through the client
side identify what Apex classes we have
access to what kind of server side
functionality we can trigger and what
kind of permissions that might access
and then third is like sign up for a
community user and become a community
user and then you'll get access to that
that sort of um ability to execute some
Apex code yourself
um and then you can also get access to
maybe different objects and stuff like
that because you're a different role is
that is that all when when you sign up
as uh I'm become like a community user
so um I wouldn't Focus too much on like
being able to execute Apex yourself I
would look towards okay what objects I
have access to and what additional
custom Apex do I have access to I'm I
it's interesting because I I would think
that if you if it exposed like a you
know a interface for you to run some
some code then I feel like you should be
able to utilize that to check the
objects that you have access to is that
is that not accurate so you can it's
just slower oh really you use yeah
because if you use my payload um for
everyone that uses burp Suite um shout
for that um you put in your payload into
like Intruder and then you put your
characters just around the the object
name and you just throw in the word list
and let it run and you just Apex you
kind of have to write like the sockle
query and then you've got to like
basically dump it into the response and
it's like an ugly response because
you're technically like putting into
like a debug
statement yeah it's not it's not you
could it's just not as
efficient okay okay solid so then you we
just Brute Force for the for the
specific object names and you've got
your the payloads in here um in the in
the article that will allow us to just
hit those specific objects um and then
we kind of iterate through and check the
permissions that we have as a community
user and maybe compare those to the ones
that we had as an anonymous user and say
okay you know here's the difference
maybe I should sort of zoom in on that
one a little bit yeah absolutely and you
can you can even possibly chain the two
you could get a list of objects as a
community user that you couldn't see
before and maybe as a guest user an
authenticated user there was Apex that
lets you put in an object name so then
you can pass it back and now you've just
elevated the criticality and you another
book so try and play around with it and
and kind of be smart about it too that's
a great idea so use try to utilize the
information that you get as a community
user saying oh I've got access to this
object I've got access to this object uh
and then take that back to
unauthenticated Apex I like that that's
that's really good all right so just
looking through here um here I'm going
to go ahead and share my screen for
those of you that are on on YouTube um
I'm I'm just scrolling through Erin's
article here on Salesforce and we're
looking at the payload glossery section
um can you just sort of talk me through
these payloads that you have um on here
and give some some context surrounding
these yeah and funly enough the first
two it's all you want it's all you need
um object related Stu yeah the rest is
just make me look better than I am at
this stuff so the first two um okay so
the first one is the payload that we use
to actually extract the data from
objects so you'll it's kind of a messy
payload but this is just the format of
the AA API um like post
data um you'll see in the entity name or
ID you'll see marker right and that's
where you put the object name okay
gotcha and it'll automatically pull
those those records for you okay but how
do we get the object name that's payload
number two so payload number two can be
run as is um it's been a long time since
I've run it so I'm not going to sure I'm
not too sure what the output's still
going to be but that would return you a
list of uh of objects so you would run
the second pillar first you would copy
all the list of objects in the response
so you've got your out of the boox
objects that Salesforce provide to like
the user object and you may also see
some custom objects that the customers
created themselves and you'll take that
you'll copy it into
Intruder and you'll use the first
payload to uh iterate over them to see
if there's any data exposed through an
access control Mis configuration okay
usually from there Justin I I'll sort by
largest response size and that's what
you know those are the tables that
typically exist right that makes sense
and and then you know we're just kind of
looking through to see what kind of data
is returned back see if we're dumping
data about other users or not okay cool
that makes sense so get get the use the
second payload to get all of the
currently available objects and then use
the first payload to get um the uh data
out of those specific objects and and
kind of see how many how many different
items we have or or what kind of
information we have access to now these
this payload that you're here you know
you put in here it like you said it is a
little bit messy and there's like this
descriptor component and then there's
like um the pams aspect uh which I I I
assume is specific to the actual
function we're calling um can you talk a
little bit about that structure uh for
the for the listeners yeah yeah and you
got to remember that like this is so
this specific payload well all of the
ones you're seeing in this article are
Salesforce created so they vendor
created Apex okay so these are Apex this
is going to be similar for all the Apex
classes somewhat yeah to a degree um
so certain things will be different so
at at the moment on on the screen like
all of that stuff um so the ID will
always be a present parameter right and
that does not matter the value of that
it doesn't matter at all okay if you
look at the
descriptor okay so that is the actual
Apex being called so the path to the
Apex code exactly exactly so get items
there at the very end so it's the suffix
so that's your Apex method okay and
selectable list provider controller is
your class that's your Apex okay class
then method right exactly um so if
you've got custom Apex naturally that'll
be a different string than than what's
apparent there um calling the scriptor
does not matter and then you've got the
Prem so the prems um the prise
parameter will always be present okay um
and naturally the parameters within that
and the values will depend on how that
Apex works so these params you're seeing
such as layout type and entity name or
ID will not apply necessarily two other
ones if you look at the second payload
it's got different parameters
um
so when we speak about like or when we
talk about custom Apex um the importance
of kind of
manually pulling apart the JavaScript to
to look for those parameter signatures
is because of this like we want to craft
a payload that's valid so that
JavaScript will contain what needs to go
in that params list
what kind of volume is expecting like a
bullion or or or a
string okay so so it's all about so in
Salesforce it's all about identifying
these Apex classes and or using these
Apex classes right the default ones from
Salesforce to query specific objects and
to try to attack Uh custom Apex classes
that the the customer has has written
and in order to do that we need to know
the descriptor right and the descriptor
contains the uh sort of a pth to the
class that is uh the Apex class and then
a specific method descriptor as well um
and then once we've got that we need to
identify the specific parameters that we
pass into that and then boom we're off
to the races we're calling that Apex
function just like sort of like we would
be in a normal rest API like you need to
identify the path to the rest API and
then the parameters that it takes for it
to actually function um and and that's
this is just the Salesforce version of
that yeah exactly and so that that's why
this article pairs really really nicely
with the um the app onni white paper on
apex uh because they complement each
each other so the white paper will
explain a lot of the format and the
reasons as to why the payloads are as
they are gotcha I'm gonna I'm gonna grab
that uh paper and put in the notes hold
on I put it in the notes already Justin
um oh perfect yeah um I will say to the
listener so if you're interested in like
digging into this or looking for it
specifically one kind of key thing to
note is uh what to search for so if you
have like some massive burp or kaido
projects and you're W to search through
them you you want to search for SLA a a
it's a word that uh Aon says kind of
funnily since he's from Ireland um I'm
just kidding it's actually a hard one to
say closer I live closer to where the
language was invented that's fair that's
fair no and or you can search for uh SLS
slash or slsf sites for Salesforce sites
um those are kind of things you can
search for and um and then with those
requests you can kind of read his blog
and kind of start to build out the
actual request sweet sweet solid okay
all right so that that covers service
now in Salesforce any any last little
shout outs or tidbits of wisdom you can
give us Arin on the on the Salesforce
front I think that's everything on the
Salesforce front to be honest with you
um it doesn't need to be too complex
like these are Tri and tested methods
that I've been using for four years
right they haven't really changed too
much so um yeah you learn learn those um
those aspects of of testing Salesforce
um communities
you've you've put yourself in a good
spot awesome okay cool um and then the
next one we had on the list here was one
that came out a little bit more recently
through app Omni which is the Microsoft
power Pages stuff um can you kind of hit
us with that research and and tell us a
bit about it yeah absolutely and and
this one's kind of
interesting in contrast to how I found
the service on the sales for stuff
because Microsoft are very very open
about like every API path so I didn't
need to spend a ton of time on the
platform to discover
um the API through which they is exposed
um so getting into that the Power
Platform is a Microsoft um of SAS
offering and it's like low code web
development you know so very very
similar to like your UI builder for uh
in service now things like that uh what
allows you to do
is drag and drop create a website um
that also can store data and fetch data
from Microsoft dataverse which is like
the
database and so it's really um
attractive because you don't really need
any prior like programming knowledge
there's no like Apex equivalent there or
like
um proprietary language associated with
it uh I had noticed when going through
the Microsoft documentation for Power
Platform and it's more specifically
power pages is what it's called yeah um
with par Pages they mention o data
feeds and there had been some research
done on o data feeds in the past as a
means to kind of exfiltrate data that's
been exposed through misconfigured
access controls again but I noticed this
banner and i' said like oh we've just
deprecated this you should use this
other API instead so I I started reading
that and it was just as simple as like _
API table name yeah dude I had that in
the notes I was like is is I love how
like we just spent so long on like
service now and Salesforce like and then
you got to hit the aura and the aura
lets you access Apex and the classes and
then when we get to power Pages you're
like yeah so there's this underscore API
path and then you hit that with the name
of the column and it just dumps like
what what is going on here man it's
funny because like slash API with no
underscore is the authenticated
one underscore as a prefix is the that's
see that's a secret path oh my God so
yeah same kind of stuff again tons of
par Pages customers were just exposing
their data through uh misconfigured
access controls so what they would do is
they would give the anonymous
user access to a way too much
information um which is funny because on
Power Platform it's kind of tricky
to expose so much data like it's it's
I'm actually surprised you have to jump
through like a couple
Hoops you got to make the table
accessible to that API then you've got
to pick which columns you want to make
accessible um for that table then you've
got to pick which role and then you've
got to pick so like the anonymous role
then you've got going to pick like okay
what who whose records should they be
able to see so there's like four steps
there so I really don't know what's been
going on with people but W yeah a ton
tons of customers were were
misconfigured it and um it was an easy
button scenario again so you could let's
say customer wanted to expose like the
first names of some users for some
public blog where people can comment or
something sure what they would do is
they they' expose
the uh the account object or something
they would intend to let's say expose
like five Fields like the first name
maybe the last name a couple things time
zone um but they didn't want to type in
all the five Fields so instead they were
like oh I'll just use the wild card and
expose like every
field and that's how it happen and then
they assign it to the anonymous role and
uh all of a sudden every column like
their address or or their phone number
um would be would be
exposed and uh yeah that's pretty much
that but the same tip applies for
this as I gave for sales force which is
you'll see in my blog I talk about the
different error messages you will
receive from the API endpoint when
you're attempting to access objects so
you'll receive uh certain error messages
that are obvious indications that it's
not accessible so you try to access an
object it'll say like insufficient
permissions or like uh even better it'll
say the objects not exposed so if it
says the objects not exposed to the API
you're done okay you're cooked if it
says something like oh the wild card is
not supported it means that you actually
have to add a Fields parameter and
manually brute force or programmatically
if you have a script which fields are
exposed so that's a good error to get
because you know you might able to get
something and then another one is oh you
don't have sufficient permissions which
is also sometimes a nice one to get
because you just self escalate by
registering once again the the
somewhat that netted me most of my
findings so I spoke about in the the NHS
so um from not in the UK it's like um
the government Healthcare body and they
exposed like um over a million um
records individuals records um and that
was through Power pages
through pair of pages okay because I
remember you reported something similar
through Salesforce like a few years ago
around Co time right organization
government's Healthcare oh that wasel
Health yeah I did finished with Ireland
I was done there I went to the UK it's
the closest isand and I was like right
you're next so um yeah that was one of
those situations where I was able to
just watch out Scotland yeah right
seriously yeah yeah I'm I'm not gonna
say too much about that but um yeah it's
it's very interesting and I also one of
the weird things about power pages is
the amount of public sector government
bodies using it like of I imagine so
just tons which was really strange
because I thought it more of like a
hobbyist developer kind of like you want
to host a Blog but uh no there's tons of
government applications across like
healthcare or like your local Council
you're signing off for like a permit or
something yeah it's something about that
pseudo Tech man like SharePoint and like
these sort of things where it's
business people love it man they're all
naturally going to be Microsoft
customers for a long time and they
probably just want to stick to the uh
what they know and it does integrate
with other kind of Microsoft products
within the the Power Platform Suite so
it does make sense um it was just
something interesting that I noted how
widely have you hunted
this
um not that widely I'll be honest with
you I was going to say I'm on a program
where I'm looking at a power page right
now so I may have you try to stay on
after the Pod to take a quick look one
thing that I did notice was their table
or I guess yeah their object names are
all custom so they're prefixed with like
the name of the app underscore then the
thing so like it's not like accounts or
contacts it's like something something
something underscore account something
something something underscore contacts
yeah the annoying thing about pair of
pages um if I recall correctly was like
you can't there's no payload like in
sales words that just give you all the
custom C objects that we found
unless those object yes exactly unless
those objects are actually being used or
embedded in the client side um maybe
something like deprecated API call it
isn't actually being made it's hard to
discover them but uh I didn't hunt that
wildly for it honestly I didn't hunt
that wildly
for anything other than Salesforce I
think Salesforce that broke my spirit a
little bit because no honestly it did
spend it and I was reporting it and
spent like two days of my life with
barely any sleep just reporting it and I
got so sick of writing
reports um so I actually started paying
my non-technical friends to like write
reports I was like my dude please just
write this yeah and then shortly after
that I just made it public I was like I
can't do this anymore like wow it just
writing reports is getting so tedious
because the guy we want man he's like I
can't write all these reports might as
well just give it to the community yeah
I mean there was no no chachy between if
if back if there was I mean yeah I would
have rinsed it completely but um no I
wasn't I wasn't doing that I I went for
uh cheap labor for my friends and then
publicly disclosing it um so so looking
through all of this I mean the the big
takeaways from from this one for me are
look for powerapps portals.com right
anywhere for that might be being used
and that's the sort of suffix for
anything running on on power power apps
here and and then once we're there we
hit that underscore API endpoint and we
try to identify what objects we can hit
and and kick back and then based off of
the given um error messages that will
come back from that API like uh resource
not found or attribute attribute star in
table contact is not enabled for the web
API or something like that um you know
going through each one of these errors
that's listed here in the um write up we
determine okay this we have access to to
this object but we don't have access to
like this field at the field level
security and then we identify what kind
of things we can access and then we dump
it all yeah yeah and the important thing
to note there is like you so what you
can't enumerate all of the castom table
names right um and you can't even really
technically enumerate the out of the box
tables what I did personally and like
anyone can do this is if you sign up for
free you just got a trial of um par
pages
uh sign up you can get access to the
entire schema the entire like out of the
box schema you can export it and just
get yourself a nice word list of all of
the default object names uh you could
then also go to GitHub or ask chbt what
the most common custom object names are
throw those
into um because yeah you can't you can't
just send a payload like sales for us to
to enumerate them uh and the other thing
I want to mention that you touched on
was um you know head we identify these
power Pages sites so we talk about like
the powerups portals.com demand I think
there is also of the top of my head I
think it's Microsoft CRM portals.com
okay like like a legacy um Legacy domain
I think it's used any longer but for for
new tenants but a lot of customers are
still on it and you will also see and
this is all in the Micosoft
documentation online for PA Pages there
are custom domains for us government too
so they will have their own um probably
because of like a Fed ramp stock or
something they need to comply with for
regulations very cool Okay so we've got
we've got Microsoft CRM portals and
power apps portals and then potentially
some other custom
stuff top my head but all on the um
Microsoft documentation online okay
we'll see if we can identify it drop it
in the notes afterwards um wow dude okay
and then let me ask you this so sign up
for this how do I get into the somewhat
authenticated state is there ever like
um and I guess this could apply to the
other um SAS providers as well is there
ever a scenario where there is you know
not a clear signup flow for the somewhat
authenticated state but you know the API
endpoint so you can hit it and be like
and register yourself in account I have
that I have that exact problem right now
there's no way to sign up in the app but
I want to be able to sign up is that
possible are you just hacking right now
yeah so what just apply all the
methodology um so yeah what what can
happen is I have seen this happen is
instead of actually disabling
registrations organizations will just
deactivate the sign up page or this is
actually even worse this is I've seen
this even more prevently is they'll just
not list the signup page in the menu on
the site right you can force pressing
you can just navigate to the signup page
um if it's just not listed but not
deactivated as well do you know do you
know what the path is or no for for what
Joseph what are you talking right now
for the for the login page on power apps
um I I I can uh I'll sync up with you
offline about that one we can take a
look but um yeah you can you can use
like Forest browsing to kind of go to
these um sign up Pages if they haven't
been fully
deactivated uh that's definitely wanted
to do it and um if people want to
identify what those points are once
again for like um Salesforce uh like
power Pages get a
trial yeah deploy a under free trials as
well deploy a website on par page or
Salesforce and look at the um URL when
you navigate to like the templated sign
up page so they'll have like a skeleton
template that you can just deploy for
like a blog or something and yeah just
copy the URL that sends to and see if
that's
uh you know exposed and not deactivated
for these for these other sites yeah so
I will say there are other paths that
are prepended with underscore since I've
been looking at one I'll mention it for
the listener there's like an underscore
Services slash and then like custom like
uh services that can be ran on the on
the back end and I think that's more
than just data it's actually running
some sort of code on the back end they
can set up like a custom service inside
of power apps and then there's slore
layout I think where you can put like a
custom HTML that you can load in the
page so uh so so there slore API slore
services and slore layout um that are
all used on power apps
Pages very cool all right man now now I
kind of got the the blood flow and now I
want to go hack this thing with uh with
Joseph um I did have one more question
Erin um what are some other big SAS
companies you kind of got your eyes on
for some more
security research that that who who
should we go pop and find configurations
on I mean yeah I mean I've got ones that
like I I haven't disclosed and published
everything yet um there's stuff in the
pipeline there is stuff in the pipeline
um I'll give you some some names because
I simply don't want to do it myself God
like all like I don't like the uis and
just not bothered anymore I'm I'm
running at a steam here guys so yeah um
I would look at organizations like sap
mhm okay gez I wonder why that's the one
you chose I mean yeah I'm not going to
say the exact reasons but I think we're
all thinking it
yeah because with we have to remember
like with sap or like um these kind of
Erp vendors not just sap other Erp
vendors I'm alluding to um they've
typically got like a suite of products
so Salesforce has like a suite of
products you've got the core Salesforce
platform which we talked about but they
also have like marketing Cloud which is
like a separate product um so sap
they've got a ton
um Adobe I've got a ton I think we all
know a w probably most of every Bug
Hunter knows what a is yeah yeah right
so that's what we're hoping for we're
hoping for like a second one of those
right um yeah look at look at getting um
getting access to those tenants
unfortunately it'll be a slow Pro
process because acquiring access is one
I set you back a little bit of money so
group together okay everyone put it in a
little bit makes it much much more
affordable uh two the process is kind of
lengthy like uh you will have it's not
just oh enter your credit card and you
know pay now you probably have to email
someone and then they'll get back to you
with a quote and then but I promise you
I promise you it'll be worth it in the
end because if you manage to get an sap
tenant you're probably the only group of
hackers with an sa tenant ever right so
you're going to find not just Mis
configs you'll probably find zero days
you'll find a ton of stuff and if you
work at it I promise you you'll make
your money back like just no question
yeah yeah 100% I uh personally would
love to see because I never figured it
out I had I obviously worked at app Omni
and one of the things that I look deeply
into was workday um uh they may or may
not have a private program floating
around there out there but um one thing
that I think would be some amazing
research let me it's like the biggest HR
platform by far and they do have a way
for you to be kind of authenticated or
sort of authenticated whatever we called
it um basically uh there are portals
where like you can sign up and apply for
jobs there's like workday like um job
portals and so you can like sign up on
there and you're given at least some
sort some form of off token and so I
think with that it'd be really
interesting if you could then pivot into
or see any data that was actually or get
access to any data that's like behind
that in the real workday tenant and I
would love to see a Hunter find that and
share it it would really um it would
bring me joy so yeah that would be huge
work day would be huge lots of lots of
cool targets out there man lots of cool
Targets in the SAS space so Ain thank
you for giving us your methodology and
some of your your thoughts on these uh
sasses that you've pwned um yeah really
appreciate it man great episode any uh
any closing thoughts uh Joseph or is
that about it no just thank you so much
Aaron it's pleasure working with you and
hopefully we can collab on stuff going
forward so yeah anything you want to
shout out
eron uh well Joseph I miss you at abon
so that's the first thing like come back
please um yeah I'd actually love to give
a shout out to my company abam I'm not
being ha to say that uh just because I
have learned so much about soci security
from working there um really really
knowledgeable group of people uh experts
in their field coming from actually
coming from sales for us and actually
coming from these organizations so um
yeah I wouldn't be the the kind of SAS
hacker that I I'm today with that uh the
folks over there so big shout out to
those guys go follow go follow aerin's
blog and his uh his Twitter SLX account
as well yeah yeah it's uh conspiracy
proof on X and enumerated doie for the
blog all right I think that's a wrap
thanks gentlemen peace peace and that's
a wrap on this episode of critical
thinking thanks so much for listening
and if you want more critical thinking
content head over to ctbb show/ Discord
join the Discord there's lots of great
conversations and chats going on over
there and if you want to support the
show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there
[Music]